Not sure if this is something I ordered
on eBay or not. It's got one of these
like straight from China, you know, with
the free delivery to your $1 item. So,
not sure if it's something I've ordered
or something somebody has sent.
Oh, yes. Oh, I remember.
I actually ordered this. I have to do a
video on it. Now, what this is is one of
these OBD2 fuel saver things. You plug
it into your OBD port on your car and
it's it's supposed to like talk to your
engine management computer and do
whatever to increase your fuel economy.
And somebody actually sent in an email
for this because they saw it on like
Facebook and all the scamiest
stuff is on Facebook and it cost like a
fortune. Um it was very expensive that
they slick website and everything. So,
let's actually look at this link that
someone sent me and it looks totally
scammy. Check it out. And
EcoFuel, choose your fuel type, gasoline
car. Look, it looks the exact one that
we got. Watch this.
EcoFuel checking three warehouses for
available stock. Yeah, I'm sure you are.
Reserving your units because I don't
want to miss out. Don't want to miss
out.
It's it's just an animated gift. They're
not really checking any of that. It's
One EcoFuel at a 50% discount.
75 bucks. Pay with PayPal. I'm surprised
they don't take Bitcoin. Um
best seller, two EcoFuels plus one for
free. Wow, you're going to want to pony
up the small amount extra for the 115
smackers to get three of them when you
can buy one for 75 bucks and get three
for 115, regularly 450 bucks. Three-year
additional warranty.
Look at this.
Lock in this great price while you still
can. Richard R from It said like three
people are currently uh in the checkout
process and stuff like David M in Palm
West just bought one Eco Fuel and these
this just keeps popping up. This is
This is hilarious.
But you can see why it just seems like
completely scammy. Pay with credit card.
Yeah, I'm going to whack my credit card
into ecofuel24.pro.
Someone just bought Andrew Long just
bought
five units and they claim all sorts of
stuff at remaps remapping the car's
computer. After driving 200 km it
adjusts itself to the car according to
the driver's habits and all that sort of
jazz and but as it turns out it was the
really expensive one is exactly the same
as this one I got on eBay for like five
bucks delivered. Fantastic. Can you get
the patent for it? Anyone? Bueller? It's
got the patent number.
I don't think so.
I expected just there to be nothing in
there but sure enough they actually have
it it looks legit and they've rubbed the
numbers off the micro there so you can't
see everything and I have actually
mapped out these pins on here and they
are the correct pins. 15% fuel saving,
two year warranty. Fantastic. This one's
actually done by a company called Nakay
also on the plastic enclosure as well
and it is a complete and utter scam. It
does not do anything at all.
Instructions are really quite vague. It
just says press the reset button for 5
seconds after plugging in release the
button just wait for a short while it'll
communicate a establish connection but
it doesn't actually tell you that the
button's actually hidden inside here
behind here and there's one little hole
for the LED but it's actually got three
LEDs in there three indicators so I I
don't know there's no other details in
here apart from how to find your OBD-II
connector so
yeah, that's it.
But look at how many cars it's
compatible with. Of course it is,
because it doesn't bloody talk to them.
All right, let's power this turd up and
see what happens. Our 12-V power is this
pin here, and it's supposed to be these
two pins up here, four and five, but
these aren't actually joined on the
board. They go off to different places.
We'll have a look at the board layout in
a minute. Let's power it on. And we've
got our LEDs.
And it's actually drawing a fair amount.
Geez.
50-odd milliamps. And if you put that on
there, you can see the LED through
there, but you can't really see the
other one, so, you know, it's really
pretty dodgy. Um
but you can see like it's trying to
connect
even though we've got nothing hooked up
to it. It's just fl- it's
flishy-flashying, and like there's no
instructions as to what that means, but
like, you know, to the casual observer,
it looks like this is doing something.
And if we hook it up to just a CAN bus
demo that's outputting like just a demo
signal, it does exactly the same
flishy-flashying.
Granted, this is not going to simulate
the data that's inside the car, but it
doesn't matter cuz this is a complete
scam. And there's another actual bus in
there which is called the K-line, which
is on the two pins next to it, and
that's an older
system, I believe. I don't know the
exact details, but the CAN bus is the
modern one. Now, it does actually seem
to have like different modes. You just
saw in that video clip where it actually
turned this LED off, and it did that for
a while, then it switched it back on,
and then the yellow LED in the center
here would like come on for like 5
seconds and then turn back off for like
20 seconds. And now, just magically,
it's come back on, and it's connected, I
guess, because they don't give you any
instructions, even though I've got a
completely fake CAN bus here. And of
course, if you disconnect it, it it
makes absolutely no difference. So, it
does the same sequence regardless of
whether or not it's sitting here with no
CAN connected, whether or not it's got
like just some sort of data pulsating on
the CAN bus, or whether or not it's in
your car.
So, here's the CAN bus on my Toyota
Corolla just under the dash here. I'm
just going to plug it in and see if it
does any difference in the little light
show that we got. And that's with the
ignition off. All right, let's turn the
ignition on.
So, I press the reset button, and it's
doing exactly the same sequence as
what's on the bench. The ignition is on,
so I'm following the instructions, and
it does
diddly squat. Anyway, I'll wait a
minute, and if I start the car up,
it's going to do exactly the same thing.
So, the way these scams work is that
they give you a fake little light show
there, and they pretend that it's
connecting
to something, when in fact it's not.
It's doing diddly squat, cuz how do you
support all these different, you know,
dozens of different model
brand cars, let alone all the different
models with all their different ECUs and
everything else. It's complete and utter
and they combine it with some,
you know, slick marketing to make you
want to buy the thing, but even for five
bucks delivered on eBay, it's still
ain't worth it.
Because it doesn't do anything. It's not
even talking to the computer.
Uh yellow LED is now switched off, and
it will
hopefully come back on for the Yeah,
there we go. Comes back on, flashes for
a little bit. It does exactly the same
sequence as what it does in the lab.
Surprise, surprise.
Oh, look. Look, it connected. It
connected in quote marks. What a load of
BS. Now, CAN bus is a differential
signal which is actually terminated with
120 ohms on either end. And if we have a
look at the CAN signal that we're
actually generating here, it's just a
test signal. You can see that here's the
ground here and it's centered around 2
and 1/2 volts here. And that's your
positive and negative line. They're just
a
classic differential signal. See?
Direct opposite. So, the CAN device in
this case, our little fake fuel saver
has to actually listen to the bus and
then try and do arbitration on the bus
to be heard and then to be able to once
it does that, it actually transmits
something. So, how can we be sure that
this thing's not talking to the CAN bus?
Cuz really we'd need like a proper ECU
connected or a accurate ECU
emulator and we'd need to sit there and
monitor this in real time over a a
fairly decent length of time to see if
it actually transmits anything to the
CAN bus at all. Well, we don't need that
because let's take a look at the board.
Okay, here's the high CAN high and CAN
low pin, okay? Well, it might look like
they're routed out. Look at this, it's
going through a 10K resistor here over
to a pin. This one, the negative here,
is going through a 10K resistor over to
under there somewhere. It's got to be
connected to a pin, doesn't it? Well,
the first thing is that you don't put
two 10Ks in series on a CAN bus. It's
terminated in 120 ohms on the bus. Lower
than that because it's like each end or
whatever. So,
like it's just not even if this thing
wanted to drive the CAN bus and could,
it couldn't do it because the two 10K
series resistors wouldn't provide the
drive capability in order to go onto the
bus, but have a look down here.
Let's just Should we zoom in a bit
closer?
What What What What The silk screen is
over the pad. That There is no solder on
that pin at all. It is not connected cuz
the pad was not exposed and that is the
That is the line leading to the CAN high
line.
Half of these pins aren't actually
connected to the board. So, you don't
need a simulator or any monitoring at
all to know this thing just physically
cannot connect to the CAN bus. It's a
scam.
So, they're actually doing a rather poor
job at this. I'd at least would have
connected it to the CAN bus even if it
didn't do anything cuz then you would
really to debunk this thing and call it
a scam, you would have to, as I said,
monitor that CAN bus in real time, have
a a simulator or emulator or whatever
for the ECU and you'd have to see that
it actually did it actually transmit
something and that's actually quite a a
complex and involved thing to do,
especially if you want to, you know,
test it over hours cuz it might sit
there monitoring for hours being uh
gathering all this data and only then
might it actually start talking to the
ECU and trying to program something, but
I like they didn't even go to that sort
of effort. So, I didn't know why they
even why they bothered with this sort of
complexity at all. It's just ridiculous,
but they've deliberately This is done at
the PCB design level. You deliberately
mask over those pins so they're not even
connected. It's just nuts. Got a 5-V
regulator here, a couple of
here to drive the LEDs, and that's and a
button to do a fake reset on the thing,
and it just goes through a light show
sequence. That's it. Just designed to
con people into thinking that it's
connected. It doesn't even show these
LEDs. Like, it's only got the one hole
for this LED here. It's just an absolute
boondoggle of a
of a device. The problem with this sort
of things people want to believe in this
sort of stuff. It's like the audio fool,
audio file, you know, uh products that
don't do anything. It's like, if you pay
like $5,000 for an IEC power cable to
hook up to your amplifier, so that's
going to increase the sound stage and
the presence and all that other
then trust me, you're going to
hear the difference because you paid
five grand for that thing. You will hear
it. Likewise, if you pay for one of
these uh fuel saving devices, there's a
very good chance that you're going to
see fuel savings because
you believe in it, and that's you're
going to like your mind's just going to
go, "Oh, yeah, it's like it's giving me
an extra, you know, mile per gallon or
whatever." I converted for you Yanks
there, you know, liters per 100 Ks here.
Because they don't do controlled proper
controlled testing, they've got no way
to actually back that up. So, you'll get
the positive reviews on the website.
There'll be a few negative ones as well,
of course, but people just ignore those
and they'll look, Joe Bloggs got like an
extra couple of miles per gallon or
something like that. So, it's got to be
a winner. It's got like four stars on
Amazon or something. And of course, the
company will add in fake reviews as
well, and these things just they can't
do anything. It's not even connected.
So, it doesn't even like monitor the CAN
bus for like signals so that at least
changed it when you turn the ignition
on. The light sequence is just the same
either way. Also, don't fall for these
scams. When you see websites with the
look and feel like the one we showed at
the start, you just know these things
are a scam. Now,
that's I said it before, there might be
genuine ECU things out there that can
actually and I know there are people out
there who modify, uh, you know, their
ECU by writing various things. You can
clear errors and do all sorts of things
that might help improve it. And I'm not
saying that's not possible because, hey,
the manufacturers do it, right? It's all
It was part of that emissions, um, scam
thing where they would have different
modes and they reprogrammed the ECU to
pass the emission standards and stuff
like that. So, you know, it is possible,
but these devices here are a complete
and utter scam. They're not even bloody
connected. Unbelievable. So, don't fall
for it. Anyway, I hope you enjoyed that
video and found it useful. If you did,
please give it a big thumbs-up and as
always, you can discuss down below. Let
us know if you actually do this
legitimately on cars cuz I'm sure I know
that there's a lot of my audience who do
automotive, uh, stuff and things like
that. So, you know, it certainly is
possible, but not with
not with one of these.
Unbelievable.
Catch you next time.